#### **YANCONG YIN**

New York, NY 10019 | (646) 236-1157 | <u>agathayin.sh@gmail.com</u> | Portfolio: <u>https://agathayin15.wixsite.com/mysite</u>

## **SUMMARY**

Highly self-motivated professional committed to pursuing a long-term career in web design. Combined expertise in graphic design and front-end programming with the ability to follow through with projects from concept to completion. Outstanding research, analytic, cooperation, and problem-solving capabilities. Background includes printing and digital media.

#### **EDUCATION**

THE NEW SCHOOL, New York

Master of Arts, Media Studies GPA 3.92/4.0 Expected 2019

Selected Coursework

Graphic and Web Design, Data mining and analysis, Programming and transforming data into visualization, Technology developments

**COMMUNICATION UNIVERSITY OF CHINA**, Beijing

Bachelor of Arts, Dutch Language and Literature GPA 3.34/4.0 July 2011 - July 2015 Minor: Journalism July 2012 - July 2014

Selected Coursework

Dutch Linguistics, Politics, Economy and Culture of the Netherlands and Belgium, Translation Skills

Journalism Theory and History, News Writing and Interview Skills, New Media Skills

#### **SELECTED ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

# Forum-like web design

Catsyard: a place for meow lovers. This project uses HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Link: <a href="http://www.livelanguage.com/yiny/index.html">http://www.livelanguage.com/yiny/index.html</a>

- Design a clean and cozy forum-like website for cat lovers
- Trials in using JavaScript coding and JQuery to increase interactions

# P5.js Data Visualization

Fake news vs fact-checking data visualization. It uses JavaScript for analyzing and P5.js for visualization. Link: http://agathayin.henryhu.net/fake-news/index.html

- Create real-time canvas showing data in diverse dimensions and scales
- Enable users to interact with the dataset and self-explore further information

### Interactive design and SVG practice

Harry Potter Fanbook website. This project practices JavaScript SVG coding and Illustration.

Link: <a href="http://agathayin.henryhu.net/HP/index.html">http://agathayin.henryhu.net/HP/index.html</a>

- Combine coding with sketching.
- Trials in simple interaction and SVG animation

#### Javascript storytelling: choice tree

Interactive website game. Based on the existing game. All images and the story belong to Akaba Studio. This project only aims to improve coding skills in creating complex tasks.

Link: <a href="http://agathayin.henryhu.net/LC/index.html">http://agathayin.henryhu.net/LC/index.html</a>

• Create mini-games and interactive choices with JavaScript

 Build a system to organize several stories into the choice tree and display the content according to interactions

### Real-time clock without hands challenge

Express time with imagination and no numbers and no clock hands

Link: http://agathayin.henryhu.net/clock/myCanvas/index.html

- Craft different scenes for daytime and night
- Use JavaScript to animate elements on the real-time canvas

#### Data analysis and tech development report

Failure or setback?: The development of the self-driving car and public feedback.

Link: data part http://portfolio.newschool.edu/yiny019/2019/05/07/figures/

Report: <a href="http://portfolio.newschool.edu/yiny019/title-failure-or-progress-the-development-of-the-self-driving-car-and-public-feedback/background/">http://portfolio.newschool.edu/yiny019/title-failure-or-progress-the-development-of-the-self-driving-car-and-public-feedback/background/</a>

- Based on studies and social media dataset
- Use Google BigQuery to analyze big data and Tableau to visualize the dataset

## **EXPERIENCE**

VIPABC, Shanghai China

**Teaching Assistant** 

Sep 2016 - Aug 2017

- Language tutoring and reading material revision
- Social media assistant created content for social media workers in English

## 51 Offer, Shanghai China

Website Editor

July 2015 - Aug 2016

- Wrote, edited, and proofread articles. Conducted article selection and provided website operation
- Content marketing collected feedback and analyzed audience metrics to record preferences
- Planned monthly column posts including content and layout
- Redesigned the website with other department's help

#### Fabang Information, Shanghai China

Social Media Intern

July 2014 - Sep 2014

- Created and edited videos
- Provided content for social media workers and assisted with content planning

## CUC Students' Association Union, Beijing China

**University Magazine Editor** 

August 2011 - May 2015

- Planned the theme contacted authors and interviewers
- Designed the Magazine layout

# **SKILLS**

#### Computer:

Experienced in Python, Skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript (JQuery, D3.js, P5.js), Bigquery (SEO)

Proficient in Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Adobe Premiere

Language: Chinese (Mandarin), English, Dutch